<?xml version="1.0"?>

<component name="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.types.TypeService">
  <documentation>
    The type service provides extension points for pluggable document types.

    Document types here can be seen as entities defining the behavior of a
    document within the ECM: they hold information about the way they will be
    managed and rendered.

    @version 1.0
    @author Anahide Tchertchian (at@nuxeo.com)
  </documentation>

  <implementation class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.types.TypeService" />

  <service>
    <provide interface="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.types.TypeManager" />
  </service>

  <extension-point name="types">
    <documentation>
      A document type has the following properties:

      - id: its string identifier

      - coretype: its core type identifier. The core type holds information
      about the document schemas {@see org.nuxeo.ecm.core.schema.types.Type}.
      WARNING: id and coretype currently need to be identical in the definition.

      - icon: icon path used to represent the document type.

      - icon-expanded: icon used for instance in tree view

      - bigIcon: icon path aimed at rich application
      
      - bigIcon-expanded: same as icon-expanded for rich application
      
      - category: Category of the document type.
      
      - description: Description of the document type.

      - label: string title.

      - subtypes: list of the allowed sub document types for a given container.
      This can be used to filter some document types creation and copy to
      specific kinds of container documents.

      - deniedSubtypes: list of forbidden sub document types for a given
      container. Useful when you inherit from another container type and
      want to restrict its subtypes.

      - default-view: this view will be returned when accessing the document.

      - create-view: this view will be returned when creating the document.

      - edit-view: this view can be used to display the document default edit
      page.

      - views: other views can be defined, so that they can be customized easily
      and trigger specific behaviour. For instance, defining a view named
      'after-edit' on the document will allow to parameter which view should be
      displayed after the document edition.

      WARNING: the views definitions and associated behaviours may change in the
      future. You should avoid customizing more than default-view and
      create-view for now.

      - layouts: the list of layouts to use in a given mode. Usual modes are
      "view", "create" and "edit". When no layouts are defined for a specific
      mode, layouts for the mode "any" are taken.

      - layout: deprecated layout configuration.

      Example:

      <code>
        <type id="Domain" coretype="Domain">
          <label>Domain</label>
          <icon>/icons/folder.gif</icon>
          <default-view>view_documents</default-view>
          <subtypes>
            <type>WorkspaceRoot</type>
            <type>SectionRoot</type>
          </subtypes>
          <deniedSubtypes>
            <type>File</type>
          </deniedSubtypes>
          <layouts mode="any">
            <layout>heading</layout>
          </layouts>
        </type>
      </code>

      Types extension point provides merging features: you can change an
      existing type definition in your custom extension point provided you use
      the same identifier.

    </documentation>

    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.types.Type" />
  </extension-point>

  <extension target="org.nuxeo.runtime.api.ServiceManagement"
    point="services">

  </extension>

</component>

