<?xml version="1.0"?>
<component name="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.actions.ActionService">
  <documentation>
    The action service provides extension points for pluggable actions and
    filters and manage UI type action compatibility (since 5.6)

    Actions are commands that can be accessed and triggered from the site pages.
    Their visibility is adapted to the current user and site possibilities using
    filters.

    @author Anahide Tchertchian (at@nuxeo.com)
  </documentation>

  <implementation class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.actions.ActionService" />

  <service>
          <provide interface="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.actions.ejb.ActionManager" />
  </service>

  <extension-point name="filters">
    <documentation>
      An action filter is a set of rules that will apply - or not - given an
      action and a context.

      Filter properties :

      - id: will be used ot identify the filter from actions definitions.

      - rules: set of rules composing the filter


      The default filter implementation uses filter rules with the following
      properties:

      - grant: boolean indicating whether this is a granting rule or a denying
      rule.

      - permission: permission like "Write" that will be checked on the context
      for the given user. A rule can hold several permissions: it applies if
      user holds at least one of them.

      - facet: facet like "Folderish" that can be set on the document type
      ({@see org.nuxeo.ecm.core.schema.types.Type}) to desribe the document type
      genral behaviour. A rule can hold several facets: it applies if current
      document in context has at least one of them.

      - group: group like "members" to check against current user in context. A rule
       can hold several groups: it applies if current user is in one of them.

      - condition: expression that can be evaluated against the current context.
      A rule can hold several conditions; it applies if at least one of the conditions
      is verified. The condition can be of the form #{somevar} or #{somevar.somemethod},
      or #{somevar.somemethod(arg)}, in which case it will be interpreted a Seam expression,
      otherwise it will be interpreted as a Jexl expression. A reference for Jexl can be found at
      http://commons.apache.org/jexl/reference/syntax.html
      The Jexl context for the expression contains the variables "document", "principal",
      and "SeamContext".

      - type: document type to check against current document in context. A rule
      can hold several types: it applies if current document is one of them. The
      fake 'Server' type is used to check the server context.

      - schema: document schema to check against current document in context. A
      rule can hold several schemas: it applies if current document has one of
      them.

      A filter is granting access to an action if, among its rules, no denying
      rule is found and at least one granting rule is found. If no rule is set,
      it is granted.

      Custom filters can be defined on the extension point, provided they follow
      the {@see org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.actions.ActionFilter} interface, using
      the following syntax:

      <code>
        <object class="my.package.MyFilter" />
      </code>

      Example of action filter using default filter implementation:

      <code>
        <filter id="theFilter">
          <rule grant="">
            <permission>Write</permission>
            <facet>Folderish</facet>
            <condition>condition</condition>
            <type>Workspace</type>
            <type>Section</type>
          </rule>
          <rule grant="false">
            <condition>condition 1</condition>
            <condition>condition 2</condition>
          </rule>
        </filter>
      </code>
    </documentation>

    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.actions.DefaultActionFilter" />
    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.actions.FilterFactory" />
  </extension-point>

  <extension-point name="actions">
    <documentation>
      An action is defined by the following properties:

      - id: string identifying the action

      - label: the action name

      - help: the action help message

      - link: string representing the command the action will trigger

      - category: a string useful to group actions that will be rendered in the
      same area of a page. An action can define several categories.

      - filter-ids: id of a filter that will be used to control the action
      visibility. An action can have several filters: it is visible if all its
      filters grant the access.

      - filter: a filter definition can be done directly within the action
      definition. It is a filter like others and can be referred by other
      actions.

      - icon: the optional icon path for this action

      - confirm: an optional javascript confirmation string that can be
      triggered when executing the command.

      - enabled: boolean indicating whether the action is currently active. This
      can be used to hide existing actions when customizing the site behaviour.

      - order: an optional integer used to sort actions within the same
      category. This attribute may be depracated in the future.

      - immediate: an optional boolean (available since 5.4.2) that makes it
      possible to call command actions without validating the enclosing form.

      - type: the UI type action (available since 5.6)

      UI Type properties, defined within a "properties" tag:
      - property: the property value
      - name: the property name

      Properties also accept list or map-like values.

      Before 5.6, it is important to understand that an action does *not*
      define the way it will be rendered: this is left to pages, templates
      and other components displaying it. Most of the time, actions will be
      rendered as command link or command buttons.

      Since 5.6, the template /incl/action/generic_action_template.xhtml handles
      rendering of an action depending on its type.

      Examples:

      <code>
        <action id="TAB_RIGHTS" link="/incl/tabs/document_rights.xhtml"
          enabled="true" label="action.view.rights" icon="/icons/file.gif"
          type="fancybox">
          <category>VIEW_ACTION_LIST</category>
          <filter-id>rights</filter-id>
          <properties>
            <property name="url">/incl/fancybox.xhtml</property>
            <propertyList name="myListProp">
              <value>item1</value>
              <value>item2</value>
            </propertyList>
            <propertyMap name="myMapProp">
              <property name="mySubProp">mySubPropValue</property>
            </propertyMap>
          </properties>
        </action>

        <action id="newFile" link="create_file" enabled="true"
          label="action.new.file" icon="/icons/action_add_file.gif" type="button">
          <category>SUBVIEW_UPPER_LIST</category>
          <filter-id>create</filter-id>
        </action>

        <action id="newSection"
          link="#{documentActions.createDocument('Section')}" enabled="true"
          label="command.create.section" icon="/icons/action_add.gif" type="icon">
          <category>SUBVIEW_UPPER_LIST</category>
          <filter id="newSection">
            <rule grant="true">
              <permission>AddChildren</permission>
              <type>SectionRoot</type>
            </rule>
          </filter>
        </action>
      </code>

      Actions extension point provides mergeing features: you can change an
      existing action definition in your custom extension point provided you use
      the same identifier.

    </documentation>
    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.actions.Action" />
  </extension-point>

  <extension-point name="typeCompatibility">
    <documentation>
      Action compatibility type (since 5.6) defining the UI type action
      from deprecated action category:

      - category: category action

      - type:
      UI action type

      Examples:

      <code>
        <typeCompatibility type="link_icon">
          <category>DOCUMENT_UPPER_ACTION</category>
          <category>DOCUMENT_HEADER_ACTIONS_LIST</category>
        </typeCompatibility>
        <typeCompatibility type="link_icon_text">
          <category>DEFAULT_LIST</category>
          <category>CLIPBOARD_LIST</category>
        </typeCompatibility>
        <typeCompatibility type="button">
          <category>CURRENT_SELECTION_COPY</category>
          <category>CLIPBOARD_PASTE</category>
          <category>CURRENT_SELECTION_ADDTOLIST</category>
          <category>CURRENT_SELECTION_TRASH</category>
          <category>CREATE_DOCUMENT_FORM</category>
          <category>EDIT_DOCUMENT_FORM</category>
        </typeCompatibility>
        <typeCompatibility type="link">
          <category>USER_SERVICES</category>
          <category>USER_MENU_ACTIONS</category>
        </typeCompatibility>
        <typeCompatibility type="bare_link">
          <category>DOCUMENT_HEADER_ACTIONS_LIST_HREF</category>
        </typeCompatibility>
      </code>

    </documentation>

    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.actions.TypeCompatibility" />
  </extension-point>
</component>
