<?xml version="1.0"?>

<component name="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.modifier.service.DocModifierService">
  <documentation>
    A document modifier alter a document binary data attached to the document.
    The service defines an extension point to associate transformation plugins
    that will perform modificaiton in binary data provided from a document
    property. The binary data is passed to the associated transformation plugin.
    The transformation result value will be set to a specified field.

    @version 1.0
    @author <a href="mailto:dm@nuxeo.com">Dragos Mihalache</a>
  </documentation>

  <implementation
    class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.modifier.service.DocModifierServiceImpl" />

  <extension-point name="docTypeToTransformer">
    <documentation>
      Extension Point for registering new document modifiers XML extensions may
      contain any number of 'docModifier' elements of the form: -

      <code>

        <docModifier name="wordMLinjectModifier" documentType="File"
          transformationPluginName="wordMLinjectPlugin" sourceFieldName="content"
          destinationFieldName="content" order="10">

          <customField name="dc:title" xmlNode="o:TitreDocument" />
          <customField name="uid" xmlNode="o:HAG" />
          ... ...
          <coreEvent>documentCreated</coreEvent>
          <coreEvent>beforeDocumentModification</coreEvent>
          ...
          <customOutputField outputParamName="titleParam" name="dc:title" />
          ...
        </docModifier>

      </code>

      - The specific tag is
      <code>
        <docModifier />
      </code>
      which is mapped on class DocModifierEPDescriptor. The following attributes
      are important for document modifier descriptor: - documentType: specifies
      the type of the document for which this document modifier will be applied.
      In this case the all documents of type 'File' will be taken into
      consideration.

      An option is to specify many document types that will be associated with
      the same modifier. For this, one could use nested elements insted of
      "documentType" attribute. Nested elements can be defined as:
      <docType>File</docType>
      <docType>Note</docType>

      <p />
      - transformationPluginName: specifies the name of the plugin that must be
      defined as an NXTransformationPlugin – and registered with Transformation
      service. This plugin will need to be able to handle binary data and some
      variable parameters list. - sourceFieldName: is the name of the document
      property that has the binary value (with runtime instance of type
      LazyBlob) - destinationFieldName: the name of the document property to put
      the new value (the result of the transformation) into. For a particular
      case it may be the same as the sourceFieldName in which case the initial
      value is replaced.

      <p />
      - The customField(s) can be defined in any number and must have one of the
      following attribute pairs: - name + xmlNode - value + xmlNode

      <p />
      - name is the name of the document property for which value is read and
      transferred as value for Property with name defined by xmlNode (due to
      change into destPropName) - value is a plain value (string) - defined
      inside the xml

      <p />
      - The coreEvent(s) should have as value the name of the core events (as
      they are defined in DocumentEventTypes class. If a core event matching one
      of the specified event names occurs, the document modifier is applied.

      <p />
      If there are many document modifiers defined for a type of Document they
      are applied sequencially.

      <p />
      Note: if no core event is specified, then the transformation will be
      applied for default core events: "documentCreated" "documentModified" -

      <p />
      Composition: If a destPropName is defined many times then the values are
      concatenated as strings if it is possible

      <p />
      - Triggering: The DocumentModifier is invoked for BEFORE_DOC_UPDATE and
      DOCUMENT_CREATED events.

    </documentation>
    <object
      class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.modifier.service.DocModifierEPDescriptor" />
  </extension-point>

  <require>org.nuxeo.ecm.core.listener.CoreEventListenerService</require>
  <extension target="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.listener.CoreEventListenerService"
    point="listener">

    <documentation>
      Register core listener that will trigger document modification.
    </documentation>

    <listener name="docModifierListener"
      class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.modifier.corelistener.DocModifierListener"
      order="130">
      <eventId>documentCreated</eventId>
      <eventId>documentModified</eventId>
    </listener>
  </extension>

</component>

