<?xml version="1.0"?>

<component name="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.search.api.client.querymodel.QueryModelService">
  <implementation
    class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.search.api.client.querymodel.QueryModelService" />

  <service>
    <provide interface="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.search.api.client.querymodel.QueryModelService" />
  </service>

  <documentation>
    The QueryModel service registers QueryModelDescriptor instances that
    are used by the QueryModelActionsBean to build QueryModel instances
    upon requests.

    A QueryModel is used to perform NXQL queries on the core with search
    parameters set dynamically. They come in two flavors: stateless and
    stateful query models:

    - Stateless query models are described by a patterned query and the
    dynamic parameters are provided as an array by the caller of the
    ``getDocument(Object[] params)`` method. See the default
    "/user_dashboard.xhtml" view for sample usage.

    - Stateful query models use an internal non persistent DocumentModel
    instance to store use editable parameters. Thus the
    ``getDocument()`` does not take any parameters since they are read
    from the document model instead. The interpretation of the
    parameters follow a structure defined by the ``whereClause``
    attribute of the QueryModelDescriptor class. A parameter *name* can occur
    several times, possibly with different values within a single where clause.

    Among other things, it's possible to register an escaper to configure
    which special characters should be escaped in fulltext-like fields (
    "escaper" attribute) for STATEFUL query models.

    Stateless ones are usually handled by some applicative code that
    can take care of this. This typically depends on both the search backend and
    the behaviour expected by the end user.

    @author Olivier Grisel (og@nuxeo.com)
  </documentation>

  <extension-point name="model">
    <object
      class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.search.api.client.querymodel.descriptor.QueryModelDescriptor" />
  <documentation>
    Registry for QueryModelDescriptor instances.

    @author Olivier Grisel (og@nuxeo.com)
  </documentation>
  </extension-point>


</component>
