<?xml version="1.0"?>
<component name="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.event.EventServiceComponent" version="1.0">
  <documentation>
    Event service
  </documentation>

  <implementation class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.event.EventServiceComponent"/>

  <service>
    <provide interface="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.event.EventService"/>
    <provide interface="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.event.EventProducer"/>
    <provide interface="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.event.EventServiceAdmin"/>
  </service>

  <extension-point name="listener">
    <documentation>
      Extension point defining event listeners.

      An event listener describes some Java code that can be executed
      synchronously or asynchronously when an event is fired by Nuxeo code.

      Example listener:
      <code>
        <listener name="mylistener" enabled="true"
            postCommit="false" async="false"
            class="org.nuxeo.ecm.platform.dublincore.listener.DublinCoreListener"
            priority="50" retryCount="1">
          <event>documentCreated</event>
          <event>documentModified</event>
        </listener>
      </code>

      The events listed are those for which the listener will be called.
      If there are none, the listener is called for all events, but this is strongly
      discouraged for performance reasons.

      Listeners belong to one of three categories:

      If postCommit=false then the listener is purely synchronous
      (also called "inline") and executed in the same thread and transaction
      as the code firing the event, as a regular method call.
      The class must implement org.nuxeo.ecm.core.event.EventListener,
      which receives events one at a time.

      If postCommit=true and async=true then the listener is purely
      asynchronous and executed at an arbitrary later point in time
      (but after the original transaction is committed), in its own thread and transaction.
      It may be retried if a ConcurrentUpdateException is detected.
      The listener is executed asynchronously by the WorkManager via a Work instance
      whose category (which determines the Work queue used) is the listener's name.
      The class must implement org.nuxeo.ecm.core.event.PostCommitEventListener,
      which receives a bundle of all the events raised by the original transaction.

      If postCommit=true and async=false then the listener is executed synchronously
      immediately after the original transaction is committed, but in a separate transaction.
      It is not executed if the original transaction does a rollback.
      All listeners in this category are executed one after the other (in priority order),
      and only after they are all done does the main thread continue execution.
      (However if one of the listeners takes too long it is left to run purely asynchronously
      and the other listeners in this category are processed.)
      The class must implement org.nuxeo.ecm.core.event.PostCommitEventListener,
      which receives a bundle of all the events raised by the original transaction.

      The priority gives a global ordering of all the listeners
      in the same category executed for a given event.
      The default is 0.

      The retryCount specifies how many times a purely asynchronous listener
      may retry execution if it resulted in a ConcurrentUpdateException.
      The default is 1.
    </documentation>
    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.event.impl.EventListenerDescriptor"/>
  </extension-point>

</component>
