<?xml version="1.0"?>
<component name="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.VersioningService">

  <service>
    <provide interface="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.VersioningService" />
  </service>

  <implementation class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.VersioningComponent" />

  <documentation>
    The versioning service hold the versioning policy used to define what
    happens to a document's version when it is created, saved, checked in,
    checked out or restored, and what version increment options (none, minor,
    major) are made available to the user.

    @Since 5.4
  </documentation>

  <extension-point name="versioningService">
    <documentation>
      Extension point defining the implementation of the versioning policy.
      Example:

      <code>
        <service class="some-class" />
      </code>

      The provided class must implement
      org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.VersioningService

      The default implementation is
      org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.StandardVersioningService You can contribute
      org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.CompatVersioningService to get pre-Nuxeo 5.4
      behavior.
    </documentation>

    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.VersioningServiceDescriptor" />

  </extension-point>

  <extension-point name="versioningRules">
    <documentation>
      CAUTION: Deprecated since 9.1, use policies, filters and restrictions extension points. Compatibility is provided,
      contribution to this endpoint will be converted to new contributions in order to preserve the initial state and
      options. The default contribution will be converted to a policy with an order equals to 10000, and each
      versioningRule will have an order equals to 10000 - idx where idx is the index of rule in VersioningComponent.

      Extension point defining default versioning rules or versioning rules by
      document type. Contributions to this XP are available for
      VersioningService implementing ExtendableVersioningService interface.

      Example:

      <code>
        <defaultVersioningRule>
          <initialState major="1" minor="0" />
          <options lifeCycleState="*">
            <none default="true" />
            <minor />
            <major />
          </options>
          <options lifeCycleState="approved">
            <none default="true" />
            <minor />
          </options>
        </defaultVersioningRule>

        <versioningRule typeName="File" enabled="true">
          <initialState major="1" minor="1" />
          <options lifeCycleState="project">
            <none />
            <minor default="true" />
          </options>
          <options lifeCycleState="approved" />
        </versioningRule>
      </code>

      The defaultVersioningRule will be used for all the document types if no
      specific versioningRule is contributed.

      typeName attribute is only available for versioningRule tag and should be
      the name of a document type.

      Initial state is the initial version number of the document. Default is
      0.0 .

      Options tag contains the different increment option available when saving
      a document. Only none, minor and major tags are used. If the default
      attribute isn't set, the first tag will be used as default. Options tag
      should always have the lifeCycleState attribute. The life cycle state name
      "*" can be used to match any state: it'll be used by default if no other
      option with a matching state exists.

      Following option gives no increment saving option when the current
      lifeCycle of the document is approved.
      <code>
        <options lifeCycleState="approved" />
      </code>

      Following options removes major increment option and set the minor
      increment option as default choice.
      <code>
        <options lifeCycleState="project">
          <none />
          <minor default="true" />
        </options>
      </code>

      If no option is specified, the defaultVersioningRule is used. If there is
      no defaultVersioningRule, we fall back on the service implementation.

      @Since 5.4.2
    </documentation>

    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.VersioningRuleDescriptor" />
    <object
      class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.DefaultVersioningRuleDescriptor" />

  </extension-point>

  <extension-point name="policies">

    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.VersioningPolicyDescriptor" />

  </extension-point>

  <extension-point name="filters">

    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.VersioningFilterDescriptor" />

  </extension-point>

  <extension-point name="restrictions">
    <documentation>
      Extension point defining restrictions of versioning option by document type. Contributions to this XP are
      available for VersioningService implementing ExtendableVersioningService interface.

      Example:

      <code>
        <restriction type="File">
          <options lifeCycleState="project">
            <option>NONE</option>
            <option default="true">MINOR</option>
          </options>
          <options lifeCycleState="approved" />
        </restriction>

        <restriction type="*">
          <options lifeCycleState="*">
            <option default="true">NONE</option>
            <option>MINOR</option>
            <option>MAJOR</option>
          </options>
          <options lifeCycleState="approved">
            <option default="true">NONE</option>
            <option>MINOR</option>
          </options>
        </restriction>
      </code>

      "type" attribute is available for restriction tag and should be the name of a document type.

      The restriction with type "*" will be used for all the document types if no specific restriction is contributed.

      Options tag contains the different increment option available when saving a document. If the default attribute
      isn't set, the first tag will be used as default. Options tag should always have the lifeCycleState attribute.
      The life cycle state name "*" can be used to match any state: it'll be used by default if no other option with
      a matching state exists.

      Following option gives no increment saving option when the current life cycle of the document is approved.
      <code>
        <options lifeCycleState="approved" />
      </code>

      Following options removes major increment option and set the minor increment option as default choice when the
      current life cycle of the document is projet.
      <code>
        <options lifeCycleState="project">
          <none />
          <minor default="true" />
        </options>
      </code>

      If no restriction is specified, the restriction with "*" is used. If there is no default restriction, we fall
      back on the service implementation (ie: none, minor and major options are available).

      @since 9.1
    </documentation>

    <object class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.VersioningRestrictionDescriptor" />

  </extension-point>

  <extension target="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.event.EventServiceComponent" point="listener">
    <listener name="versioninglistener" async="false" postCommit="false" priority="1000"
              class="org.nuxeo.ecm.core.versioning.VersioningListener">
      <event>beforeDocumentModification</event>
    </listener>
  </extension>

</component>
